(
"ai_sub_version": "3.6.0",
"generated_at": "2026-10-10T22:41:25.481255",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.8-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"service_tier": null,
"service_tier_subtitles": null,
"service_tier_lyrics": null,
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
のーいーじゃーーー！
Noooijaaa~!
うーん。
Hmm...
あらあら。
Oh dear.
めらめら。
Flaring up.
あちちめらー！
Achichi mera~!
の、のいじゃ。
No- noija.
ホロライブあそびまわり隊、ご利益担当の火消し妖狐サラマンダー、
Hololive Asobimawaritai's salamander kitsune firefighter in charge of blessings,
あちちめらなのじゃー！のじゃー！
I am Achichi Mela! Noja~!
今日は...
Today...
なんていうゲームをやるかと言うと...
as for what game I'll be playing...
よいしょ。
Alright.
今日は何というゲームをやるかと言うと...
As for what game I'll be playing today...
スパゲーーット！
SPAGHET!
というゲームで...
...is the game...
遊んでいくのじゃ。
...that I'll be playing, noja.
知らないゲーム！なんか名前だけ知ってるゲーム！
A game I know nothing about! A game I only know by name!
名前だけ知ってるゲーム、なんかホロライブで流行ってるらしいという知識のみ。
A game I only know by name, with only the knowledge that it's popular in Hololive.
ホロライブで流行っていて...
It's popular in Hololive, and...
えっとね、フブキ先輩にね、いただいたんじゃが...
Umm, you see, Fubuki-senpai gifted it to me...
あの、フブキ先輩がゲームの説明してくれたから読むのじゃ。
Umm, Fubuki-senpai gave me a description of the game, so I'll read it, noja.
メッセージでね。ちょっと待って、大きくする。
In a message. Hold on, let me enlarge it.
えっとね...うーんと...よいしょ。
Umm... Let's see... There.
「あなたはスパゲッティーが好きですか？
\"Do you like spaghetti?
それは結構、でしたら益々好きになりますよ！
That's fine, you'll love it even more!
とても簡単！スパゲッティーを温めるだけ！とっても楽しい世界があなたを待っています。
It's so simple! Just warm up the spaghetti! A wonderful world awaits you.
初心者でも安心、アットホームなスパゲッティーです！
Safe for beginners, a cozy spaghetti party!
これであなたもスパゲッティーのことが好きになります、今すぐダウンロード！」
With this, you will love spaghetti too, download now!\"
ね、そのコマンドーってなんなのじゃ？
Hey, what's this 'Commando' thing?
コマンドーってなんなのじゃ、わしそれ知らない。
What is Commando? I don't know it.
ね、わしそれ知らない。配信で触れてもいいやつ？
Hey, I don't know it. Is it something okay to mention on stream?
なんか知らないミームってさ、あの、ワンチャンさ、
Because with memes I don't know, like, there's a chance...
配信で、あの、言っちゃダメな、さ、あのミームである可能性があるからさ、ちょっとすごい怖いんじゃけど...
...it might be a meme you shouldn't say on stream, so I'm honestly pretty scared...
平気？いいやつ？
Is it okay? A safe one?
あ、映画！映画！
Ah, a movie! A movie!
のじゃ、のじゃ、のじゃ。なるほどのじゃ。
Noja, noja, noja. I see, noja.
なるほどのじゃ。映画か。
I see, noja. A movie, huh.
よかった。なんか、あの...
Thank goodness. I was like...
ヤバいネタかと思った。
I thought it was a sketchy joke.
『コマンドー』っていう映画の構文なんじゃの？
So it's copypasta from a movie called \"Commando\"?
なんかその、Twitterでこれツイートしたときの引率にも確か、
In the quote retweets when I tweeted about this on Twitter,
なんか「コマンドー構文」みたいなん書いてあって、なんじゃろって思ってた。
people were writing stuff like \"Commando copypasta\", so I was wondering what that was.
なんじゃろって思ったけど、調べたらこのパスタの、もしかしてこのパスタのゲームのネタバレになる可能性があると思って...
I wondered what it was, but thought searching it might spoil this pasta game...
うん。
Yeah.
パスタのゲームがどういうゲームかのネタバレになっちゃうかなと思ってね、
I thought it might spoil what kind of game this pasta game is,
見るのをね、やめ...調べるのをね、やめましたのじゃ。
so I stopped look... stopped looking it up, noja.
よいしょ
All right.
よいしょ、よいしょ
Here we go, here we go.
のじゃ
*Noja.*
ニコニコ発のミームは知らない
I don't know memes that originated on Nico Nico.
うん
Yeah.
なんか
Like...
ニコニコ動画
Nico Nico Douga...
通ってないから
I didn't grow up with it,
知らない
so I don't know them—
わし、ニコニコ動画のミーム
Nico Nico Douga memes, that is.
何で知らないかというと
As for why I don't know them...
あの、インターネット始めて
Well, after I first got on the internet,
あの
um...
じゃから
so...
あの、良くないことが起きて
something bad happened,
家特定されて
my address got identified,
あの、父と母に拾われて
and I was taken in by my father and mother.
で父と母に拾われた時に
And when they took me in,
なんか、わしがまた掲示板とか危ないサイトを見たら良くないみたいな
they felt it'd be bad if I looked at message boards or risky sites again.
そう
Yeah.
なんか、わしの、なんかそのセキュリティ？何て言うの？
Like, my... what do you call it, security?
あの
Um...
何て言うんだっけ？あの、フィルタリング？
What was it called again? Filtering?
フィルタリングみたいなのですっごい厳しい設定にされて
They put really strict parental filtering on me,
そう
yeah.
めっちゃ、じゃから、そっから厳しい設定にされちゃったから
So because it was set so strictly from then on,
ニコニコ動画もYouTubeも、その時期の全部見れてないのじゃ
I couldn't watch Nico Nico Douga or YouTube from that era at all.
そう
Yeah.
そう、キッズフィルター。キッズフィルターかけられて
Right, a kids' filter. They put a kids' filter on,
キッズフィルターかけられて、ガチ何にも見れてなくて
and with that, I seriously couldn't watch anything.
そう
Yeah.
じゃから、ニコニコ動画も、あの、それの対象となって
So Nico Nico Douga was blocked by that too,
そう、ニコニコ動画もYouTubeも見れてないのじゃ、だから
and that's why I couldn't watch Nico Nico Douga or YouTube.
そう、基本的にインターネットの楽しいサイト全部フィルターされた
Basically, all the fun sites on the internet got filtered.
うん
Yeah.
Twitterとかもダメじゃった
Twitter and stuff were blocked too.
うん
Yeah.
そう、YouTubeもダメだった
Yeah, YouTube was blocked as well.
それほどわしが危ないことをしたということ
That's how dangerous the things I did were.
うん
Yeah.
のじゃ
Indeed.
そう、だから、古のニコニコ動画は全然通ってないけど
So I never experienced ancient Nico Nico Douga at all,
でも最近は見よるよ、ニコニコ
but lately I do watch Nico Nico.
あの、ボカコレ？VOCALOID Collectionの時だけ
Um, only during Vocacolle—The VOCALOID Collection—
ニコニコ動画めっちゃ見るよ、わし
do I watch a ton of Nico Nico Douga.
うん
Yeah.
ボカロ曲を聴くために！
To listen to Vocaloid songs!
ボカロPさんがニコニコ動画にさ、先に動画あげるからさ
Because Vocaloid producers post their videos to Nico Nico first.
早く聴きたいから
I want to listen to them ASAP,
ニコニコ動画で見るのじゃ
so I watch them on Nico Nico Douga.
「最近のニコニコってどうなん？」
"How is Nico Nico these days?"
え、知らない。ボカコレのことしか知らない、わしは
Eh, I don't know. I only know about Vocacolle.
それ以外のカテゴリーはあんま見ないから
I don't really watch other categories,
あまり詳しくないのじゃ
so I'm not very familiar with it.
「スマホ取り上げられなかった？」
"Didn't they confiscate your phone?"
いや、あれはもうほぼ取り上げたと言っても過言ではないのじゃ
No, it wouldn't be an exaggeration to say it was pretty much confiscated.
ほぼスマホ取り上げですのじゃ
It was practically phone confiscation!
ほぼ取り上げられてた
It was practically taken away.
なんか、あの、キッズケータイみたいな
Like, um, a kids' phone...
なんか電話、その連絡先にしか電話できないキッズケータイみたいなのを持たされてた記憶あり
I remember being given a kids' phone where you could only call preset contacts.
うん
Yeah.
え、そう「ついに始まりました」なのじゃ
Yeah, "it has finally begun."
そう
Right.
わし、400歳なのに
Even though I'm 400 years old...
わし400歳なのに！キッズケータイ持たされてた
Even though I'm 400 years old, they gave me a kids' phone!
うん
Yeah.
そう、なんかもうほぼ、ほぼ防犯ブザーみたいな機能のやつ
Yeah, one that pretty much just functioned as a personal safety alarm.
防犯ブザーみたいな機能がついてるキッズケータイを持たされてた記憶あり
I remember being made to carry a kids' phone with a safety alarm feature.
うん
Yeah.
あと外で電波が繋がらない、SIMが入ってないiPhoneを持たされていた記憶あり
Also, I remember being made to carry an iPhone with no SIM card that couldn't get signal outside.
Wi-Fiが繋がってるとこしか使えないけど、使えるサイトも制限されてるみたいな
It only worked where there was Wi-Fi, but even the sites I could use were restricted.
うん
Yeah.
ほぼたまごっちですのじゃ
It was practically a Tamagotchi!
うん
Yeah.
そう、ガラケーと変わらんのじゃ
Yeah, no different from a flip phone!
うん
Yeah.
のじゃ
Indeed.
そう、心配だったっぽい
Yeah, apparently they were worried.
心配だったっぽい
Apparently they were worried.
わしがネットで危ないことするから、「ヤバい、この...」
Because I did dangerous things online, like, "Oh no, this..."
「この子を成長させるまで、このサラマンダーが」
"Until this child grows up, until this salamander..."
「リテラシーを身につけて成長するまで、スマホを持たせてはいけない」って思わしたっぽい
"...learns media literacy and matures, we can't let her have a smartphone." That's what they thought.
うん
Yeah.
そう、反動で今ドパマンダーになってるのじゃ
Yeah, and from the rebound, I've become a "Dopamander" now!
ド反動ですのじゃ
A total rebound!
当時...
Back then...
え、そう、だからさ、結構さ、ニコニコ動画とかその古のインターネットミームとか
Yeah, so like, Nico Nico Douga or ancient internet memes...
そのわしが禁止されてた時期に流行った、あの
the stuff that was trending during the time I was banned from the internet...
コンテンツみたいなのを知ってる人が羨ましいのじゃ
I'm really envious of people who know about that content!
わしその時期触れなかったから
Because I couldn't touch the internet during that time.
うん
Yeah.
反動というのは、誰にでも訪れますのじゃ
A rebound comes for everyone.
「友達と話合わなくならなかった？」
"Didn't you stop fitting in with your friends' talks?"
えぇぇ...？
Ehhh...?
友だち...？
Friends...?
のじゃあ...
Well now...
え、ど...なんか...
Uh, what... like...
そう...
Well...
そんな、その...
Like, back then...
そんな、その時めっちゃ仲いい子がいなかった...
I didn't really have anyone I was super close with...
その... 要はその、わしが...
Like... Basically, back when I...
あの、キッズフィルタリングみたいなされてた頃は、やっぱ...
...was under that kids filtering restriction thing, you know...
人間低学年、だ、しょ...
When I was in lower human grades—like, ele—
人間で言うところの、小学生とか中学生の頃じゃろう？
...in human terms, elementary or middle school age, right?
え、その頃って結構、なんか...
And back then, you know...
見た目で迫害みたいなあったから。
...there was kind of persecution based on looks,
角とか尻尾とか生えてたし、わし。
'cause I had horns and a tail growing out and all.
なんか、あんまり馴染めなかった記憶...
I remember not really fitting in back then...
た、楽しいゲームするか！楽しいゲームするのじゃ！
L-Let's play a fun game! Let's play a fun game!
す、スパゲッティの、アットホームな、アットホームなスパゲッティのゲーム...
A s-spaghetti... homey... A homey spaghetti game...
アットホームなスパゲッティのゲームするのじゃ。
I'm gonna play a homey spaghetti game!
うん、のじゃ。うん。
Yeah, that's right. Yep.
なんか、うん、そ、そうなのじゃ。
Yeah... Y-Yeah, that's right.
よいしょ、よいしょ。
All right, all right.
パスタ冷めちゃう？ええっと...
The pasta will get cold? Um...
ええっと、ちょっと待つのじゃ。
Um, hold on a second.
うん。
Yeah.
あ、でもでもでも！補足、補足！1点補足！
Ah, but wait, wait, wait! One point of clarification!
でも、あの...
But, um...
わしが人間に擬態する術を身につけてからは、
...after I learned the art of disguising myself as a human,
あの、友達とかもでき始めたし、から、
I started making friends and all, so...
あの、安心してほしいのじゃ。うん、安心してほしいのじゃ。
...I want you not to worry! Yeah, don't worry about me.
パスタ、パスタ食べる。パスタ食べる。ええっとね...
Pasta, gonna eat pasta. Gonna eat pasta. Um...
そう、どうやらアットホームな...
Right, so apparently it's a homey...
アットホームなスパゲッティってなんじゃ？
What even is "homey spaghetti"?
アットホームなスパゲッティらしい。
Apparently it's homey spaghetti.
アットホームなスパゲッティ...
Homey spaghetti...
「初心者でも安心」安心ってなんじゃ？
"Safe for beginners"—what does that even mean?
あんまりその、スパゲッティを形容する言葉として...
As words to describe spaghetti, that's not really...
初心者でも、ま、「初心者でも安心」はゲームに対してかな？
Well, maybe "safe for beginners" refers to the game?
ゲームに対しての形容する言葉なのかな。
Is it describing the game?
アットホーム言わない。
You don't call it "homey."
言わない気がする。
I don't think people say that.
から、なんじゃろ？フブキ先輩ミームが使いたかったのかな？
So... did Fubuki-senpai just want to use a meme?
わしその、コマンドミーム？知らないから...
I don't really know command memes and stuff, so...
なんか、「初心者でも安心」「アットホームな」みたいなのも、ミームの言葉なのかな？
Is stuff like "safe for beginners" and "homey" also part of the meme?
そこまで含めて構文みたいな感じなのかな？
Is the whole phrasing part of the copypasta template?
ごめんね、ミームの元ネタが知らないからさ。どこまでがミームのあれなのかわかんなくて。
Sorry, I don't know the original meme, so I can't tell where the meme ends.
ふんふんふん。
Mm-hmm, mm-hmm.
でもわし、わしの知ってる人間豆知識披露していい？
But hey, can I share some human trivia that I know?
わしの知ってる人間豆知識なんだけど、
It's some trivia about humans that I know, but...
あの、人間の、職場？
...in human workplaces?
なんか、仕事？雇用？
Like, jobs? Employment?
雇用募集みたいなので「アットホーム」って言葉が...
When job recruitment ads use the word "homey"...
書かれてるのは、アットホームじゃないってのを聞いたのじゃ。
...I heard it actually means it's not homey at all!
それだけ知ってるのじゃ。
That's all I know about it.
人間が使う「アットホーム」って言葉は、なんかすごい空気が悪いらしい...
When humans say "homey," the atmosphere is apparently super toxic...
...との噂。
...or so the rumor goes.
わしが人間と関わってる間に身につけた豆知識。
That's trivia I picked up while interacting with humans.
「ということは」って何？
What do you mean by "which means..."?
空気悪いの？このスパゲッティ。人間関係とかある感じ？
Is the vibe toxic? In this spaghetti? Like workplace drama?
このゲーム、このゲーム人間関係あるのじゃ？
Does this game have human relationships drama?!
ん？
Hm?
対人ゲーか？
Is it a PvP game?
A PvP game?
うん。
Yeah.
でもなんか、やっぱ、新人に...
But really, giving a game...
新人にさ、ゲームくれるフブキ先輩めっちゃ優しいですのじゃ。
...giving a game to a newcomer, Fubuki-senpai is so incredibly kind!
めっちゃ優しいのじゃ。から、あの、嬉しい、ありがとうございますって思うのじゃ。
She's so kind! So I'm just so happy and grateful to her.
あと、おかゆ先輩にもね、あの、ゲームをね、いただいていてね。
Also, Okayu-senpai gifted me a game too!
あの、たんぽぽのやつとか、いただいてるから、
Like that dandelion one she gave me,
それもまたやりたいなって思ってますのじゃ。
so I'd love to play that one again sometime too.
先輩優しいのじゃ。
My senpai are so sweet.
まだ、わし新人じゃし、あんまりお話もしたことないのに...
I'm still a newcomer and haven't talked to them much...
ゲーム送ってくれるなんて。
...yet they sent me games.
え、だってゲームって結構好きな人にしか送らないよね？
I mean, you only gift games to people you really like, right?
え、じゃない？なんか...
Right? Isn't that so?
結構ゲームを送るってことは親密度さ、高めなんじゃない？
Gifting a game must mean our bond is pretty close, isn't it?
高めなんじゃない？
Pretty close, right?
あの、お近づきの印的にさ、
Like, as a token of getting closer,
なんか、仲良くなりたいって思ってるんじゃない？わしと！ねえ？
doesn't it mean they want to be good friends with me?! Right?
え、だからすごい、すごい嬉しくて！そう！
So I'm just so, so happy! Yeah!
すごい連絡いただいたときはめちゃくちゃ嬉しくて。
When they messaged me, I was overwhelmingly happy.
楽しみなのじゃー！
I'm so excited!
嬉しいのじゃー！
I'm so happy!
じゃあ、ゲームやるお部屋に行こうかの。
All right, shall we head over to the game screen?
よいしょ。
Up we go.
よいしょー！
Here we go!
のちゃー！
Nochaa!
ん。
Mm.
よ。
Yo.
よいしょ。
All right.
音量、どれくらいがいいんかの？
Wonder what volume level is good?
ちょっとした音しか入ってないけど。
There are only faint sounds right now, but...
音量もうちょい上げるか。
Maybe turn up the volume a bit more.
オーディオボリューム...
Audio volume...
これぐらいにしとくか。
Let's leave it around here.
これぐらいでいい？
Is this good?
ちっちゃい？
Is it too low?
まだちっちゃい？
Is it still quiet?
どうかのう
I wonder...
開始してみないと分からん、ま、確かに。
You can't tell until we start. Yeah, that's true.
割とこのちっちゃめの音じゃとね
With this kind of quiet sound,
あんま分かんないよね。
you can't really tell.
よいしょ。
Alright.
Here we go.
いい感じ？
Good now?
え、でもさ、わしなんかさ、
Wait, but you know...
この、このなんか、これ気になってて
I've been kind of curious about this...
何？これ。
What is this?
ちょっと画面ちっちゃいの使っとるから、あんま見えないんじゃけど、
I'm using a small screen so I can't really see it, but...
目が赤い。
Its eyes are red.
目が赤いのがおる。
There's something with red eyes.
何？
What is it?
これはまた別？
Is this something else?
映画とか？
Like a movie?
なんじゃろう？
I wonder what it is.
謎なんのじゃ。
It's a mystery.
広告？
An ad?
広告的なあれか。
Ah, an advertisement?
広告だからあんま気にしなくていいか。
Since it's an ad, I guess I don't need to worry.
よし、じゃあ
Alright then,
一旦PLAYを
let's try clicking
押してみますのじゃ。
"PLAY" first.
よいしょ。
Here goes.
ふむふむ。
Mm-hmm.
手？
Hands?
手と、部屋かな？
Hands and... a room?
キッチンだ！
It's a kitchen!
キッチンにおりますのじゃ。広い！
I'm in a kitchen! It's so big!
え、暗い...
Whoa, it's dark...
広くて高め、
It's spacious and expensive-looking...
贅沢めのお家。
A fancy house.
贅沢めのお家。Look at the Spaghet to see the Slap Sequence.
A fancy house. "Look at the Spaghet to see the Slap Sequence."
Slap the Spaghet... スラップって
"Slap the Spaghet"... Slap means...
叩く？
to slap?
ん？
Huh?
スラップってわしの思ってるスラップと一緒？
Is "slap" the same slap I'm thinking of?
ん？
Hmm?
英語の意味が違う？
Does it mean something different in English?
スラップって叩く？
"Slap" means to hit, right?
叩く以外に意味があるのじゃ？
Does it have any other meaning?
ん？
Wait...
調理ゲーって聞いたのじゃ。
I heard this was a cooking game.
ん？
Huh?
一旦進めるか。
Let's just keep going.
えー、Slap the Spaghet by clicking the correct mouse button in the sequence.
Um, "Slap the Spaghet by clicking the correct mouse button in the sequence."
マウスを押して操作する系か。
So you play by clicking the mouse.
マウスのボタンを押して...
Click the mouse buttons...
マウスのボタンってどうすんや？
How do I do the mouse buttons?
マウスのボタンを押して、えー、操作します。
You click the mouse buttons to, um, play.
Complete sequences to keep the Spaghet warm.
ほう。
Oh.
温める？
Keep it warm?
ほう。
Hmm.
ん？
Wait...
これ、わしの英語合ってる？
Is my English correct here?
なんか、スパゲッティを叩いて温めるって書いてない？
Doesn't it say to slap the spaghetti to keep it warm?
気のせい？
Am I imagining things?
摩擦的な？
Like friction?
人間ってそういう能力があるのじゃ？
Do humans have that kind of ability?
え、人間、人間って手でさ、パスタ叩いたら温められるの？わしそれ知らない！
Wait, humans can warm up pasta just by slapping it with their hands?! I didn't know that!
サラマンダーそれ出来ないのじゃ！
Salamanders can't do that!
え、人間って結構万能なのでは？
Wait, aren't humans pretty all-powerful then?
Complete sequences to keep the Spaghet warm.
Try to complete the first sequence.
ほう。
I see.
ん？
Hmm?
これは、レフト、ライト、レフトか？
Is this Left, Right, Left?
SLAPって出てくるけど... SLAPって出てくるけど！
It literally says SLAP... It really says SLAP!
え？
Huh?
「ボヨン」言うたよ。
It made a "boing" sound.
「ボヨン」言うたのじゃ。
It just went "boing"!
何これ？
What is this?
どういこっ... ん？
What does this... huh?
これで温まるのじゃ？
This warms it up?
こっ... ん？
Th-... huh?
一旦チュートリアルやるか。
Let's just do the tutorial.
え、L？
Uh, L?
手、汚れちゃうよ...
Your hands will get dirty...
人間はこういうのができるのじゃ？
Humans can really do stuff like this?
熱エネルギー的な？
Like thermal energy?
のじゃ？
Right?
なんか、左上に、寒いマークと熱いマークがある。
There's a cold icon and a hot icon in the top left.
これで温めてることになるのじゃ？
Does this count as warming it up?
ほう。
Oh.
Each completed sequence increases the Temperature Meter above.
あ、左上の温度が、叩くと温度が上がるらしい。
Ah, the temperature in the top left goes up when you slap it, apparently.
温めるってそういうこと？
That's what it means by warming it up?
レンチンとかじゃないのじゃ？
Not like microwaving it?
レンチンは最近の話なのじゃ？
Is microwaving a recent invention?
この時代は手で温めてたのじゃ？
In this era, did they warm it up by hand?
If the Temperature Meter gets too low...
温度が低くなってしまったら、
If the temperature gets too low,
the Spaghet will freeze?!
スパゲッティ凍っちゃうらしい！
Apparently the spaghetti will freeze!
みんなそうしてる？
Does everyone do this?
あ、みんなそうしてるんだ...
Ah, everyone does this...
知らなかった。
I had no idea.
「レンチンが古い」？レンジが古い？！
"Microwaves are old"? Microwaves are old?!
でも手汚れちゃうよ、むしろ！
But your hands will get dirty instead!
ほう... え、でも、ホラーゲームだから、
I see... But wait, since it's a horror game,
なんか、温めないと、
if you don't warm it up,
この左上のメーターが一番左に行っちゃうと、
and that meter in the top left reaches the far left,
パスタが冷めちゃって、
the pasta will cool down,
凍っちゃうらしい。凍るって何？
and freeze, apparently. Wait, freeze?!
氷ってそんな簡単に作っていいのじゃ？
Can ice really be made that easily?!
If that happens...
its all over...
全てが終わりだって！どういうこと？！
It says it's all over! What does that mean?!
本気すぎじゃろ！
Taking it way too seriously!
パスタの温めに。
Over warming up pasta!
"Press [A] to continue" のじゃ?
"Press [A] to continue", right?
なんか思ってたのと違うのじゃ。
This is kinda different from what I expected.
なんか クッキングゲームみたいな クッキングシミュレーター的なのを想像してきたのじゃ。
I imagined something like a cooking game, a Cooking Simulator-style game.
なんか 湯切りして パスタを何分茹でて湯切りして
Like draining the pasta, boiling it for a few minutes, straining it...
あのソースかけて 客に提供するみたいな。
...pouring sauce on it, and serving it to customers.
え? ゲームってさ そういうの あるよね?
Wait, games like that exist, right?
なんか パスタシミュレーターみたいな。
Like a pasta simulator or something.
のじゃ?
Right?
Let's cooking?
人間はこれが普通なのじゃ?
Is this normal for humans?
人間は こういうのが...
Do humans...
好きなの?!
...like this kind of thing?!
ええ...
Well...
はい。"If you click the incorrect mouse"... 間違ったマウス押してしまうと マウスボタン押してしまうと
Alright. "If you click the incorrect mouse..." If you click the wrong mouse, the wrong mouse button...
"you'll punch the Spaghet." ほう。
..."you'll punch the Spaghet." Oho.
ああ これはあれかな? あの ゲーム性じゃ。
Ah, is this what they call gameplay mechanics?
なるほど。間違ったボタン押しちゃうと 叩くじゃなくて殴るになってしまうらしいのじゃ。
I see. If you press the wrong button, it turns into punching instead of slapping.
"This will cause the temperature to drop faster." あ
"This will cause the temperature to drop faster." Ah...
殴ると ホントは叩かなきゃいけないのを殴ってしまうと
If you punch it, if you punch it instead of slapping it...
温度が急激に落ちてしまって 冷えやすくなっちゃうのかな?
...the temperature drops rapidly and it cools down faster, maybe?
"Complete the next 4 sequences."
ええ ライト ライト ライト。
Let's see: right, right, right.
な 何これ?
Wh-What is this?
ぺちょんぺちょん言ってる... ぺ ぺ ぺちょんぺちょん言ってるけど。
It's making squishy sounds... Squish, squish, it's making squishy sounds.
ぺちょん ぺちょんぺちょん言ってるけど。
Squish, squish, squishing sounds.
音ゲーなのじゃ?
Is this a rhythm game?
ん?
Hm?
"In the top right corner of the screen, there is a Visibility Meter."
なんかあるよね 右にな。
There is something on the right, yeah.
"This meter fills whenever an unwanted spectator watches you." どういうこと?
"This meter fills whenever an unwanted spectator watches you." What does that mean?
何が見てるの?
What is watching?
"If the meter fills completely, you lose." 負けます。
"If the meter fills completely, you lose." You lose.
何?!
What?!
調理ゲーと聞いている! 調理ゲーと聞いていますのじゃ!
I was told this was a cooking game! I was told it's a cooking game!
調理ゲーかと思ったら音ゲーじゃし
I thought it was a cooking game, but it's a rhythm game, and...
ホラーゲー?! これが?!
A horror game?! This is?!
競合なのじゃ? 自社コンテンツの競合コンテンツですのじゃ?
Is this competition? A rival to our company's content?
それを回してるのじゃ? それはいいの?
And I'm streaming it? Is that really okay?
え "Let's avoid that. Look down at the arrow."
Uh, "Let's avoid that. Look down at the arrow."
"Left Click when you see HIDE to crouch behind the counter." あ
"Left Click when you see HIDE to crouch behind the counter." Ah...
隠れられるんだ。
...so you can hide.
何が見てるの わしを?
What is watching me?
何が見てるの?
What's watching?
なんか 何かがわしのことを見てるっぽくて なんか隠れたりもできるらしいけど...
Apparently something is watching me, and I can hide from it too, but...
"Left Click when you see HIDE"... HIDE どうやってやるんじゃ?
"Left Click when you see HIDE"... How do I hide?
ちょ 今んとこない。
Wait, there's nothing right now.
今んとこなさそう。
Doesn't seem to be anything right now.
あ あった。
Ah, there it is!
なるほど。下に行くとHIDE 下に行くと隠れられるっぽい。
I see. Looking down gives HIDE. Looking down lets me hide.
誰から隠れてるのじゃ?
Who am I hiding from?
え "While down here, you can't be seen by anyone on the other side of the counter."
Uh, "While down here, you can't be seen by anyone on the other side of the counter."
向こう側にいる人の誰からも見られなくなります ここに隠れてるからね。
No one on the other side can see you, because you're hiding here, right?
"Keep in mind that you are still exposed on your side. Press [A] to continue." ほう。
"Keep in mind that you are still exposed on your side. Press [A] to continue." I see.
どういうこと?
What does that mean?
これ な 何 何をするゲームなのじゃ?
Wh-What kind of game is this?
"To stand, look up at the arrow on the edge of the counter. Left Click when you see STAND UP." オッケー。スタンドアップ?
"To stand, look up at the arrow on the edge of the counter. Left Click when you see STAND UP." Okay. Stand up?
ほう ほう ほう。
Right, right, right.
"In the event that there is a threat on this side of the counter, you'll need to hide..."
なるほど?
I see?
また別のとこに隠れる必要もあるらしい。
Apparently I need to hide somewhere else too.
"To do so, look at the arrow ahead of you, on the opposite side of the counter." 逆側にも隠れられますよと。
"To do so, look at the arrow ahead of you, on the opposite side of the counter." You can hide on the opposite side too.
"JUMP ACROSS"?
ジャンプアクロス?!
Jump across?!
飛んで逃げられるのじゃ?!
You can jump and run away?!
ほう。
Oho.
"Try it out." 試せ。
"Try it out." Give it a try.
"To return from that side, look up at the arrow on the edge of the counter, and Left Click when you see JUMP BACK."
"Press [A] when you're back behind the original side of the counter to continue."
ん? 何から隠れてるの?
Hm? What am I hiding from?
なんか 逃げ 逃げ要素ありということ?
Wait, does that mean there's an evasion element?
ほう。
Oho.
逃げ要素あり? ほう。
An evasion element? I see.
アクションゲーム?
An action game?
ほう。
Oho.
まあ やってみるか。
Well, let's try it out.
はい。"This concludes the tutorial."
Alright. "This concludes the tutorial."
"To view this information again, you can enable it in the Settings menu. Press [A] to close."
はい。まあ 大体 大体分かったのじゃ。
Alright. Well, I basically get it.
大体言いたいことは分かった。
I get the general idea of what it's saying.
うん
Yeah.
やってみるか
Let's give it a try.
ジャンプ アクロス
"Jump across."
何？何？何？
What? What? What?
何何何何？！
What, what, what, what?!
何が起きた？何が起きた？
What happened?! What happened?!
何？何？何？
What? What? What?
待って、何？何？
Wait, what? What?
なんかすごい音する！
There's a crazy sound!
え、絶対動いちゃダメな…何？な、ちょっ…
Wait, am I definitely not supposed to move...? What? W-wait...
え、パスタ…
Wait, pasta...
え？なんでこ…なんでこんな暗い？え？
Huh? Why is it... Why is it so dark? Huh?
おん？ん？あ、わしミスったっぽい？
Hm? Mm? Ah, did I mess up?
何？何？何の音？何の音？！
What? What? What's that sound?! What is that sound?!
何？何の音？何の音？
What? What's that sound? What's that sound?
何の音がしてんのじゃ？！
What kind of sound is that, noja?!
な、う、あ、パニックになっちゃった！
Wh- ugh, ah, I'm totally panicking!
ん、のじゃーー！
N-nojaaa!
なん、今何が起きてる？なんかすごい音する。
What- what's going on right now? It's making a crazy sound.
ホラーゲームみたいな音する！
It sounds like a horror game!
ホラーゲームみたいな音するのじゃ！
It sounds like a horror game, noja!
ね、る、る、ブオーって音する！何？！
It's making this loud groaning sound! What?!
ああああああ！助けて助けて助けて！あああ！
Aaaahhh! Help me, help me, help me! Aaaah!
あああ！やばい！なんか自滅しちゃった！
Aah! Crap! I ended up killing myself!
自滅しちゃった！自滅しちゃった！
I killed myself! I killed myself!
何？！何なのじゃ？！何ーーー？！
What?! What was that, noja?! What?!
これ映っていいやつ？
Was that okay to show on stream?
なんか、なんか出しちゃった！
I, I pulled something up!
なんか出たのじゃ！なんか出た！なんか出た！
Something popped up, noja! Something popped up! Something popped up!
のじゃ？何？
Noja? What?
待って、何のゲーム？
Wait, what kind of game is this?
おや？
Hold on?
ほ、ホラー？え、これホラーなのじゃ？
Ho- horror? Wait, is this a horror game, noja?
これ…
Isn't this...
これクッキングゲームじゃない？
Isn't this supposed to be a cooking game?
これクッキングゲームじゃない？もしかして。
Isn't this a cooking game? Could it be...?
びっくりしたー。
That scared me...
え？
Huh?
フブキ先輩？
Fubuki-senpai?
フブキ先輩、わしの…
Fubuki-senpai, to me...
フブキ先輩、わしと仲良くなりたいからゲーム送ってくれたんじゃないの？
Didn't you send me this game because you wanted us to get closer?
フブキ先輩、わしのこと嫌い？
Fubuki-senpai, do you hate me?
何？な、のじゃ？
What? Wh- noja?
な、のじゃ？
N-noja?
ちょ、一旦水飲んで落ち着いていい？
Wait, can I drink some water and calm down for a second?
心臓がバクバクしてて…
My heart is pounding like crazy...
のじゃ？
Noja?
これ洗礼なのじゃ？
Is this an initiation ritual, noja?
これ洗礼？
Is this an initiation?
あ、チェンメールってそういう…
Ah, so that's what chain mail is...
チェーンメールって…
Chain mail...
あの、被害者を増やすためにある？
Um, does it exist just to create more victims?
底知れぬ人間の悪意？
The bottomless malice of human beings?
いや、狐なのじゃ。
No, she's a fox, noja.
のじゃ？
Noja?
え、すごい心臓バクバクしてる。
My heart is pounding so hard.
び、び、びっくりしたー。
Th-that really startled me...
ん？これ、せ、あのさ、一応教えてほしいんじゃけど…
Hm? Is this... um, could you guys tell me something?
これは、パスタを叩き続ければいいわけじゃない？
For this, is it not just about slapping the pasta?
逃げ、隠れたりもしなきゃいけない？
Do I have to run, or like, hide as well?
いつ隠…ん？いつ隠れるのがいいの？
When do I hi... hm? When is a good time to hide?
なんか、ちょっ、パ、パニックになっちゃって…
I kind of just went into a total panic...
い、一旦もう一回やるか。
L-let's try one more time.
叩きながら隠れる？
Hide while slapping?
叩きながら隠れなきゃいけない？
Do I have to hide while slapping?
あの目が、あの目のゲージがどうなって…
That eye... how does that eye gauge work...
マックスになったら来る？
Does it come when it reaches max?
テレビ見るといい？
Should I look at the TV?
テレビ？
The TV?
テレビどれ？
Which one is the TV?
何？何？
What? What?
テレビ見るといいって言ったよ？
You guys said looking at the TV is good!
テレビ見るといいって言った、テレビ見えない！
You said to look at the TV, but I can't see the TV!
テレビ見えない！
I can't see the TV!
テレビ指示が来る？
Do instructions show up on the TV?
ステイ アウェイ フロム... ゴールド？
"Stay away from... gold"?
ん？どういうこと？
Hm? What does that mean?
あああああああああああああああ！
Aaaaaaaaaaaahhh!
ねえ！嘘！ねえ、死んだ！
No way! Hey, I died!
ん？
Hm?
のじゃ。
Noja.
え、今は？
Wait, just now?
え、今は本当はどうしなきゃいけなかった？
What was I actually supposed to do just now?
今は？
Just now...
今は... カウンターを取り替えなきゃ...
Was I supposed to switch the counter...?
なんか... 頭がごちゃごちゃ...
My head's all jumbled up...
のじゃ...
Noja...
お、おば？
A-A ghost?
し... ん？ さっきと違うお化けだった？ それもわかんなかったのじゃ。
W-Huh? Was that a different ghost from before? I couldn't even tell, noja.
さっきと違うやつだった？ 反対側に？
Was it different from earlier? On the opposite side?
のじゃ...
Noja...
暇があったら叩く。
Slap when there's free time.
ゴールディが来たら飛び越える。
Jump across when Goldie comes.
足音が聞こえたらすぐに飛び越える。
As soon as you hear footsteps, jump across.
はぁーん... あぁ...
I see... Ah...
数種類いる？
There are multiple types?
ゲーム性...
Gameplay depth...
ゲーム性ーー！
Gameplay depth!
キャラによって対応が違う？
Different reactions depending on the character?
はぁ... え、ホラゲーやん。
Ah... wait, that's just a horror game!
ほ... 音？
Th-The sound?
音怖いのじゃ。
The sound is scary, noja.
ちょ、い、もう1回やるか。
W-Wait, should I try one more time?
うーん。
Hmm.
テレビ見る？
Watch TV?
はい、テレビ！
Okay, TV!
何？ テレビ、テレビ見る、テレビ見る！ テレビ見る！
What? The TV, watch the TV, watch the TV! Watch the TV!
見えない！
I can't see it!
ちょ、テレビ見えないのじゃ。
Wait, I can't see the TV, noja.
あ。
Ah.
テレビ見えない。テレビなんも載ってない。
I can't see the TV. There's nothing on the TV.
あ、あった！「STAY AWAY FROM GO...」えっと、JUMP ACROSS！
Ah, there it is! "STAY AWAY FROM GO..." Um, JUMP ACROSS!
こういうこと！ こういうこと！
Like this! Like this!
いいんじゃない？ 上手なんじゃない？
Isn't this good? Aren't I doing well?
あ、い、いいんじゃない？
Ah, i-isn't this good?
え、来てる、来てる、来てる！
Wait, it's coming, it's coming, it's coming!
お前、来てるじゃん！ 来てるじゃん！ お前、馬鹿野郎！ 来てるじゃん！ 来てるのじゃ！
Hey, it came! It came! You bastard! It came! It's here, noja!
なんで？！ え？！ 跳べって言うた... 跳べっつたじゃん！ 跳べっつた！ ねえ！
Why?! Huh?! You said jump... You told me to jump! You said jump! Hey!
跳べって言われた！ コメント欄に跳べって言われたじゃん！ 何？！ 嘘つきがいます！
I was told to jump! The chat told me to jump! What?! There are liars here!
え？ ん？ 早すぎた？
Eh? Hm? Was it too early?
え、わしが悪いの？ 今。
Wait, was it my fault just now?
今わしが悪い？ 早すぎる？！
Was that on me? Too early?!
のじゃぁぁ...
Nojaaa...
と、速い？ タ、タイミング？
T-Too fast? Th-The timing?
出てから跳ぶ？ 足音... あ、
Jump after it appears? Footsteps... ah,
えし...「馬鹿野郎」とか言ってごめんなのじゃー。
S-Sorry for calling you a bastard, noja...
あの、他責良くないのじゃ。
Blaming others isn't good, noja.
タイミングゲー？ 音ゲー？ こんなとこでも？
A timing game? A rhythm game? Even here?
引きつけてから避ける？
Lure it in, then dodge?
のじゃあ...
Noja...
なるほど。音を聞く... え、ぐって怖い音を大きくすると...
I see. Listen for the sound... If I turn up the creepy sounds...
ホラゲーみたいな音する。
It sounds like a horror game.
怖いのじゃ...
It's scary, noja...
びっくりしたー。え、これ...
That scared me... Wait, is it...
毎回こんなびっくりするの？
going to scare me like this every time?
のじゃぁ...
Nojaaa...
よ... ん、もう1回するーのじゃ。
Al... yeah, I'll try one more time, noja.
アットホームってそういう...
Is "at-home" like that...
い、家、家で行われる... 的な？
Li-like, taking place in a home... kind of thing?
家で行われるゲームのアットホームのじゃ？
An "at-home" game because it takes place at home, noja?
全パターンできれば慣れる？ わしの心臓持つ？
Will I get used to it if I learn all patterns? Will my heart hold out?
だいぶもう... だいぶ... だいぶバクバク...
It's already... totally... totally pounding...
行くのじゃ！
Here I go, noja!
はい。
Okay.
のじゃ。L、L、L！
Noja. L, L, L!
ある、見る！
There is one, watch!
はい、見る！ テレビ！
Okay, watch! The TV!
テレビ鳴ってないじゃん。テレビ載ってないじゃん。
The TV isn't playing anything. There's nothing on the TV.
ヒントちょうだい。
Give me a hint.
ひっ、あ、来た！
Eek, ah, here it is!
「BABY STRIKES WHAT MOVES」
"BABY STRIKES WHAT MOVES"
どういう意味？
What does that mean?
隠れる、隠れる。隠れる、隠れる。
Hide, hide. Hide, hide.
うわぁぁああ！ なんでぇぇ？！ なんでこうなるのじゃぁぁ！！
Waaahhh! Whyyy?! Why does this keep happening, nojaaa?!
ぬ...
Nu...
びっくりした...
That scared me...
あ、動かない言われてたのに隠れたからダメ？
Ah, it said not to move, so did I fail because I hid?
オッケーのじゃ。パターン、パターン、パターン、パターンね。パターン覚えるのじゃ。
Okay, noja. Patterns, patterns, patterns... patterns, right. I'll memorize the patterns, noja.
えっと... えっと...
Um... um...
いや、わし咄嗟の、あの、咄嗟の英語無理。咄嗟の英語無理のじゃ。
No, sudden... um, sudden English is impossible for me. Sudden English is impossible, noja.
ベイ... 赤ちゃんが来たら動かない。
Bab-... When the baby comes, don't move.
赤ちゃんが来たら動かない。
When the baby comes, don't move.
ちょ... ね、覚えゲーなのにさ、覚えるたびにびっくりさせられるの何？！
Wait... why does a memorization game scare the crap out of me every time I try to learn?!
のじゃぁ...
Nojaaa...
4パターン。4パターンだって。
Four patterns. They say there are four patterns.
えっと、4、4ならいける、4ならいける。えっと...
Um, f-four should be doable, four should be doable. Um...
あの、あ、もう忘れた。なんか、ジャンプして向こうに行くやつと...
Um, ah, I already forgot. Like, the one where you jump across, and...
えっと... 止まるやつと...
Um... the one where you stop, and...
行くのじゃ。
Here I go, noja.
えっと、あ
Um, ah...
え、何何？
Eh, what, what?
あ、のじゃ
Ah, noja.
レフト、ライト、レフト、ライト
Left, right, left, right...
ライト、ライト、レフト、ライト、レフト
Right, right, left, right, left...
レフト、レフト、レフト
Left, left, left...
レフト、レフト、ライト、ライト、あ、来た、来た
Left, left, right, right... Ah, it came, it came!
ベイビー、あ、動かない！動かない！
Baby! Ah, don't move! Don't move!
わし分かる！わし分かる！はい動かない！
I know! I know this! Okay, don't move!
はい動... ななな、怖いのやめて！
Okay, don't mo-- N-n-no, it's scary, stop it!
やめてのじゃ！いるのやめて！見たくないのじゃ！
Stop it-noja! Stop being there! I don't want to look-noja!
いや、いや、はい、消える！
No, no... Okay, he disappears!
はい、動かす！レフト、ライト、ライト！
Okay, slapping! Left, right, right!
ライト、レフト、ライト、ライト、来た、なんか来た
Right, left, right, right, it came, something came!
ステイ・アウェイ・フロム...
Stay away from...
あ、これタイミング、タイミング
Ah, this is about timing, timing.
足音聞こえたら？はい、隠れる！
When I hear footsteps? Okay, hide!
いいんじゃない？いいんじゃない？
Isn't this going well? Isn't this good?
消えた
It disappeared.
パパ、ヘイト、ビー、ビーイング... 見えない
Papa hates be... being... I can't read it.
ビーイングウォッチ、見られるのが嫌いだって。見る！
"Being watched." He hates being watched. Look!
見る！見る！見る！見る！見る！見る！見る！見る！
Stare! Stare! Stare! Stare! Stare! Stare! Stare! Stare!
見る！お前を！お前を見る！
Stare! At you! I'm staring right at you!
はい、消える！雑魚！乙！
Okay, he's gone! You scrub! GG!
何？
What?
え？こ、凍っちゃった！ね、凍っちゃ... キャーー！
Eh? It froze! Hey, it fro-- Aaaah!
やったのじゃ！
What the heck-noja!
わしやったよ？
I was doing it right, though?
わし... わし上手かったのに！
I was... I was doing so well!
ええね、のじゃあ...
Man, noja...
びっくりしたー
That scared me...
え、でも凍ったら画面見なきゃいいんじゃない？
Wait, but if it freezes, shouldn't I just look away from the screen?
凍ったら、凍ったら画面見なきゃいいんじゃない？
If it freezes, shouldn't I just not look at the screen?
え、これどれぐらいのスコア出すのがすごいの？どれぐらいを狙うのじゃ？
What kind of score is considered good here? How much should I aim for-noja?
これキリないよね多分。1時間とかできる人もいるの？
There's probably no end to this. Are there people who can last like an hour?
何なのじゃ？でもワンミニッツできたよ、ワンミニッツ。うん。
What is this-noja? But I lasted one minute, one minute! Yeah.
40分？
40 minutes?
40分パスタを叩き続ける？
Slapping pasta for 40 minutes straight?
またまた40分？
40 minutes, really?
正気かのじゃ？
Are they in their right mind-noja?
パスタを？
Slapping pasta?
のじゃ？
Noja?
行くのじゃ！
Here I go-noja!
はい、ライト、レフト、ライト、エル、エル、エル、エル、はい
Okay, right, left, right, L, L, L, L, okay!
はい、ライト、ライト、レフト、ライト、ライト、ライト、レフト
Okay, right, right, left, right, right, right, left...
レフト、レフト、レフト、ライト、ライト、レフト
Left, left, left, right, right, left...
ライト、ライト、ライト、ライト
Right, right, right, right...
あ、Stay away from... あ、来た！
Ah, "Stay away from..." Ah, it came!
行くよ
Here it goes.
足音聞こえたら...
When I hear footsteps...
上手、上手なんじゃない？上手な...
Doing great! Aren't I doing great? Do--
あ、早い早い！早くない？行ける？行けるか？
Ah, fast, fast! Isn't it fast? Can I make it? Can I?
はい行ける！
Yes I can!
はい神のじゃ！
Yes, I'm a god-noja!
え、パパ、パパね、パパ。了解
Papa, Papa, right? Papa. Roger that.
はい、見る、見る、見る、見る！
Okay, stare, stare, stare, stare!
はい、はい、雑魚乙！雑魚乙のじゃ！
Yes, yes, scrub, bye! Scrub, bye-noja!
見られるのに弱い！
So weak to being watched!
はい、はい、はい、はい、はい、はい、はい、はい、はい
Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes...
もう分かったのじゃ。もうこのゲームの攻略を見つけたのじゃ
I've got it figured out-noja! I found the strat for this game-noja!
ベイビー、ベイビーね、オッケーオッケー。動かない、動かない！
Baby, baby, right? Okay, okay. Don't move, don't move!
ノー・ムーブですね、のじゃー！ノー・ムーブのパ、のズ、のー、のじゃー！
No moving, right-noja! No moving... -noja!
ふぅー
Phew...
勝った、勝った
I won, I won!
え、もう分かった。もうこのゲーム分かったのじゃ
I totally get it now. I've mastered this game-noja.
ドント・レット・ママ・シー・ユー
"Don't let Mama see you."
ママに見られ... え、これ流石にこっちなんじゃない？
Seen by Mama... Wait, wouldn't it obviously be this way?
はい、はい！
Yes, yes!
上手なんじゃない？上手なんじゃない？
Aren't I good at this? Aren't I good?
もう消えた？
Did she disappear already?
Don't look at me
え、なんかすごい怖い音
Eh, what a super scary sound.
え、何？すご... パスタ冷めちゃう
Wait, what? It's so... The pasta's gonna get cold!
え、パスタ冷めちゃう
Hey, the pasta's gonna get cold!
ねぇパスタ冷めちゃう
The pasta's gonna get cold!
Hey, the pasta's gonna get cold!
え、パスタ冷めちゃう
Wait, the pasta's gonna get cold!
何？
What?
キャーーー！うわーー！何！
Kyaaaa! Uwaaa! What?!
今のは何、今のは何が悪かったのじゃ？
What was that? What did I do wrong just now-noja?
パパも来てた？え、ど、ど、同時？同時ってあり？
Was Papa there too? Wait, a-at the same time? Is that allowed?
ねぇ同時ってなし！同時はずる！同時はずるなのじゃ！
Hey, at the same time is unfair! Same time is cheating! Cheating-noja!
だって、ど、赤ちゃんちゃんと同時に来たら動けないじゃん！
I mean, if it comes at the same time as the baby, I can't move!
指示変わってる？
Did the instruction change?
わしが隠れてたあいだに、ママが消えて...
While I was hiding, Mama disappeared, and...
声を聞く...
Listen for the voice...
ちょ、一旦水飲んで... ちょっと...
Let me just drink some water... hold on...
ちょ、あの、あのね、あ、あのね、びっくり度の頻度が高い！
W-wait, um, you know, you know, the frequency of jump scares is too high!
あの、びっくり... びっくり度の頻度が高い... 高くて
Um, the scare... the frequency of jump scares is so high... it's so high and...
あの、高いのじゃ...
Um, it's just so high-noja...
ちょ水、水を... はぁ...
S-some water, water... haah...
なんか... び... お... のじゃ...
Like... sca... oh... noja...
うあぁ… し、し、心臓が…
Ugh... M-M-My heart...
心臓がバクバクして…
My heart is pounding out of my chest...
これ、ジャンプスケアの登竜門…なのかな？
Is this... like a rite of passage for jumpscares?
これ、慣れる気がしませんのじゃ。
I don't think I can ever get used to this.
ちょ、トースターでダメなんじゃよ、わし。
I mean, even a toaster popping scares me.
行くのじゃ。
Here I go.
よいしょ。パスタ冷めちゃう。
Alright. The pasta's gonna get cold.
レ、ライト、ライト、レフト… レフト、ライト、ライト…
R-Right, right, left... Left, right, right...
ライト、レフト、レフト… ライト、レフト、レフト…
Right, left, left... Right, left, left...
レフト、レフト、ライト…
Left, left, right...
ん、レフ… んー、ライト、ライト、ライト…
Lef... mm, right, right, right...
ライト、ライト、レフト…
Right, right, left...
レフト、レ… の、のじゃ。
Left, le... Okay.
STAY AWAY FROM… オッケーのじゃ。
"Stay away from"... Okay then.
待って、のじゃ。
Wait a sec.
上手、上手。上手。
Nice, nice. Nice.
よいしょ。上手。
Up we go. Good.
ベイビー、ベイビー！止まる、止まる。止まる、止まる。
Baby, baby! Stop, stop. Stop, stop.
止まる、止まる。ベイビー、止まる。はい、ベイビー、止まる、止まる。
Stop, stop. Baby, stop. Yes, baby, stop, stop.
上手、上手。パ、パスタ冷めちゃう！消えて！
Good, good. Th-The pasta's gonna get cold! Go away!
パスタ冷めちゃう。
The pasta's gonna get cold.
パパ、パパね。
Papa, got it.
はい、見る、見る、見る、見る、見る、見る、見る！見る、見る、見る！見る、見る、見る、見る、見る、見る！お前！
Okay, look, look, look, look, look! Look, look, look! Look, look, look, look, look! You!
はい、女の子と目を合わせられないのじゃ！
Ha, you can't even make eye contact with a girl!
あ、ぐ…
Ah, guh...
DON'T LET MAMA SEE、オッケー？
"Don't let Mama see", okay?
はい。隠れる？
Okay. Hide?
もう消えたんじゃない？流石に。
She must be gone by now, right?
うおーい！いるーー！
Whoaa! She's right there!!
え、パパの音しない？
Wait, isn't that Papa's sound?
パパの音しない？
Isn't that Papa's sound?
パパの音する！
That's definitely Papa's sound!
見る、見る、見る、見る、お前…見、見てる、見てる！
Look, look, look, look, you... Lo- Looking, looking!
見てるのじゃ！見てるのじゃ！
I'm looking! I'm looking!
はい、はい、はい、はい。
Yes, yes, yes, yes.
レフト、レフト、ライト、ライト、レフト、レフト…
Left, left, right, right, left, left...
レフト、レフト、ライト、レフト、レフト、ライト…
Left, left, right, left, left, right...
るるるるるるるる… るるるるる…
L-L-L-L-L-L-L-L... R-R-R-R-R...
何？何？なんかいる。
What? What? Something's there.
ぎゃあああーー！
Gyaaaahhh!!
足音来たら、飛び越える。
When footsteps approach, jump over.
え、ねえ、テレビにヒント無かったよ？
Wait, hey, wasn't there supposed to be a hint on the TV?
ねえ、テレビに、テレビにヒント無かった？！
Hey, wasn't there a hint on the TV?!
ねえ、テレビにヒント無かった？え、それも、そんなのアリ？
Hey, wasn't there a hint on TV? Wait, is that even allowed?
ねえ、そんなのナシ！
Hey, no way!
そんなのナシじゃ！
That's unfair!
テレビ途中から消える？言ってよ！
The TV turns off halfway through? You should've told me!
テレビ、チュートリアル？
Was the TV just a tutorial?
テレビ見てればいいやって思ってた… え、じゃあ赤ちゃんどうするの？
I thought I just had to watch the TV... Wait, then what do I do about the baby?
赤ちゃんどうするのじゃ？
What do I do about the baby?!
赤ちゃん無理！
The baby is impossible!
ねえ、赤ちゃんって… んーのじゃ。
Hey, what about the baby... Mmm.
感覚？音？
Intuition? Sound?
うーん… え、じゃあもう赤ちゃんの音覚えるしかない。
Ugh... Then I guess I just have to memorize the baby's sound.
あの…あの、駆け寄ってきたら飛び越えるのは分かって…
Um... I know that when it rushes over, I have to jump...
なんか低い音がしたら、あの、見、見るのは分かって…
And when there's a low sound, I know I'm supposed to l-look...
ママの音が分からない。ママと赤ちゃんの音が分からない。
I don't know Mama's sound. I can't tell Mama's and the baby's sounds apart.
赤ちゃんは「キャハハ」って音？ちょ、ちゃんとそれを聞こう？
Does the baby make a "kyahaha" laugh? W-Wait, let me listen carefully for that.
いや、聞く余裕ないのじゃ！怖いんよ！
No, I don't have the luxury to listen! It's too scary!
のじゃ… 音ゲー？これ音ゲーか？
Good grief... A rhythm game? Is this a rhythm game?
のじゃ。
Alright.
ライト、ライト、レフト。
Right, right, left.
ライト、レフト、ライト。
Right, left, right.
レフト、レフト、ライト。
Left, left, right.
レフト、レフト、レフト…
Left, left, left...
レフト、レフト、ライト…
Left, left, right...
ライト、ライト、レフト…
Right, right, left...
レフト、レフト、ライト…
Left, left, right...
レフト、レフト…
Left, left...
DON'T LET MAMA… あ、ママの声覚えよう。
"Don't let Mama"... Ah, let's memorize Mama's voice.
ママの声覚えよう。
Let's memorize Mama's voice.
おー、お化けみたいなこと言ってるのじゃ。お化けみたいなこと言ってる。
Ooh, sounds like a ghost talking. Sounds just like a ghost.
え？いるやん。
Huh? He's right there!
ん？いないやん。
Wait? He's not there.
な、のじゃ？何？
Wh-what? What?
PAPA HATES、オッケー、パパね。
"Papa hates", okay, Papa.
パパはそんな怖くない。
Papa isn't that scary.
だって、見てればいい。ほら。
After all, I just have to look at him. See?
「DON'T LOOK AT ME」つってる。あ、嫌なこと言ってんだ。
He's saying "Don't look at me"! Ah, he says what he hates!
「DON'T LOOK AT ME」つってる。
He's saying "Don't look at me"!
あ。
Ah.
のじゃ、のじゃ、のじゃ、のじゃ。
Noja, noja, noja, noja.
ベイビーね？ベイビーの音も覚えよう。
Baby, right? Let's memorize the baby's sound too.
あ、動いちゃった。
Ah, I moved.
あはは！「あはは」って言ってる！
Ahaha! It's saying "ahaha"!
で、これが消える音。
And that's the sound of it leaving.
うん、うん、うん。
Mm-hmm, mm-hmm.
STAY AWAY FROM… あ、来た。
"Stay away from"... Ah, here it comes.
はい、これでシューで…
Okay, then I slide over and...
はいはい
Alright, alright.
シューって音したら Stay away from なのかな？
If there's a whooshing sound, does that mean stay away from it?
のじゃのじゃ
Let's see, let's see.
オッケー、ん
Okay, hmm.
レフト、レフト、レフト、ライト、ライト
Left, left, left, right, right...
これ何だっけ？お化けは隠れる
What was this again? For the ghost, I hide.
Don't look at me が、お父さん？
"Don't look at me" is... Dad?
お父さん？
Dad?
見てるやん
He's looking right at me!
あっ
Ah!
のじゃ、のじゃ、のじゃ、のじゃ
Okay, okay, okay, okay...
のじゃ、のじゃ、のじゃ、のじゃ、のじゃ、のじゃ
Okay, okay, okay, okay, okay, okay...
あ、赤ちゃん
Ah, the baby!
赤ちゃん？
The baby?
ライト、ライト、ライト、レフト、レフト
Right, right, right, left, left...
隠れる
I'll hide.
消えたから戻る
It vanished, so I'll go back.
あっためる
Warm it up...
レフト、レフト、ライト、レフト、ライト、レフト、レフト、レフト
Left, left, right, left, right, left, left, left...
え、何だっけこいつ？
Wait, what does this guy do?
うわああ！何で、何でお前！ん！
Waaah! Why, why you?! Agh!
何だっけそいつ！
What was that guy again?!
そいつ何？！
What is he?!
そいつ何？！そいつ何のじゃ？
What is he?! What does he do?!
そいつ何の人じゃ？
Who the heck is that guy?!
笑う奴何だっけ？！
What do I do for the laughing one?!
何だっけそいつ？！
What was he again?!
あ、赤ちゃん？
Ah, the baby?
赤ちゃんって何のあれだったっけ？
What was I supposed to do for the baby again?
あ、何の敵か分かんなかった
Ah, I didn't even know what enemy that was.
そうじゃんか
That's right!
やはり慣れ、慣れのじゃ
It's all about getting used to it, getting used to it!
ああ、なんか驚きが、驚きがマシになってきた
Ah, the jumpscares are getting easier to handle!
驚き、驚きがマシになってきたのじゃ！
The jumpscares are getting way easier to handle now!
もう、もう怖くない！
I'm not... I'm not scared anymore!
さすがに、さすがにもう行けるのじゃ！
Surely, surely I can do it now!
ふうう〜
Phew...
あ、もう、もう、もう余裕なのじゃ
Ah, it's totally... totally a breeze now!
ホロライブホラゲ担当行かせていただきますのじゃ
I'll gladly take the title of hololive's horror game specialist!
いくらでも、いくらでも、いくらでもいけるのじゃ
I can keep going as much as needed!
もう勝ったのじゃ。毎週やるのじゃホラゲ
I've basically won. I'll play horror games every week!
毎週ホラーゲームして、あの、結局ホラゲって覚えゲーじゃから
I'll play horror games every week, and ultimately horror games are all about memorization.
パパね
That's Papa, right.
あの、もうびっくりってね、あの見え、見えてしまったら
Once the surprise... once you've already seen them,
もう覚えてしまったら何も怖くないのじゃ
and once you've memorized it, there's nothing scary at all!
あの、初めて見る驚きが人間を苦しめている...
It's just the initial shock that torments humans...
サラマンダーを苦しめているだけじゃから
that torments this salamander!
毎週やってホラゲ全パターン覚えたら、全然怖くないのじゃ
If I play weekly and memorize every horror game pattern, it won't be scary at all!
うん
Yeah.
あ、やべ
Ah, shoot.
お化けで隠れる
Hide from the ghost...
あれは消える音？のじゃ
Was that the sound of it disappearing? Okay.
毎週ホラゲやる、やって耐性つけるのじゃ
I'll play horror games every week to build up tolerance!
ベイビーね
Baby, okay.
これが、あ、視界が近くに見えたら...
If this... ah, if it gets too close in your vision...
赤子
The baby!
分かった！
Got it!
Stay? オッケー
Stay? Okay.
逃げる
Run!
消える
It vanished.
のじゃ
Okay.
ライト、ライト、レフト、ライト、ライト、レフト、レフト、レフト
Right, right, left, right, right, left, left, left...
レフト、レフト、ライト、ライト、レフト、ライト、レフト、ライト、レフト、ライト、ライト、レフト、ライト
Left, left, right, right, left, right, left, right...
隠れる
Hide.
消える
It's gone.
のじゃ
Okay.
レフト、レフト、ライト、ライト、ライト、ライト
Left, left, right, right, right, right...
レフト、レフト、ライト、ライト、レフト、ライト、ライト、レフト、レフト
Left, left, right, right, left, right, right, left, left...
何だっけ？
What was this?
あ、逆！逆！逆！逆！逆！
Ah, wrong way! Wrong way! Wrong way!
え、消えた。なんか間違えたけど消えた。ラッキー
Wait, it's gone! I messed up, but it went away. Lucky!
間違えたけど消えたのじゃ
I messed up, but it went away!
お父さん見るのじゃ！
Look at Dad!
はい、見るのじゃセカンド！
Okay, keep looking, second time!
のじゃ！
Done!
のじゃ、のじゃ
Alright, alright...
あ、もう理解したのじゃ、完全に
Ah, I understand it completely now!
もう覚えちゃったらね、やっぱこういうのって...
Once you memorize it, games like this are...
何だっけ？赤ちゃん
What was it? Baby!
止まる
Stop!
消える
It's gone.
え、何でわしパスタ叩いとるの、それで？
Wait, why am I slapping pasta anyway?
わし何でパスタ叩いてるの？
Why am I slapping pasta?!
これ、何... 何をしていらっしゃる方？
What is this... who on earth are you?
ん？違う。隠れる
Huh? No. Hide!
え、位置違うじゃん
Wait, the position is different!
ママ、ママあの位置で出なかった？
Mama... didn't Mama appear over there?
あの位置パパしか出なかったのに、違う位置でも群れてる
Only Papa used to appear in that spot, but they're gathering in different spots too!
位置変わると困る！
Switching positions is not fair!
そんなのアリ？！
Is that even allowed?!
ま、でも応用か
Well, I guess it's an adaptation.
なんか時間が進むにつれて変わっていく
It seems to change as time progresses.
お父さん見る、お父さん見る
Look at Dad, look at Dad...
お父さん見る。お父さん奥ね
Look at Dad. Dad's in the back, right.
あ、間違えた
Ah, I messed up!
間違えたけどなんかここで許される
I messed up, but somehow it let me off here.
何でじゃ？
Why, though?
何でか分からないけど...
I don't know why, but...
なんか対角に飛ばなくてもいいっぽい
Looks like I don't necessarily have to jump diagonally.
なんじゃ？
What?
なぜだか...
For some reason...
許され...
I was spared...
謎
A mystery.
ライト、レフト、ライト...
Right, left, right...
のじゃ、頭がおかしくなってくるのじゃ
My head is starting to get confused.
わしは何をして...
What am I even doing...?
なんやっけ？
What was it again?
ハイド
Hide.
消える？
Gone?
え、なんか対角じゃなくていいじゃん全然
Wait, it totally doesn't have to be diagonal!
なんで？
Why?
ね、パスタ難しくない？
Hey, isn't the pasta hard?
ね、パスタが難しい！
Hey, the pasta is hard!
パスタが難しい
The pasta is so hard.
パスタが難しいのじゃ
The pasta is so difficult.
パスタ、こ、凍っちゃう！
The pasta... It-It's gonna freeze!
音ゲー、音ゲー、自信なし！
Rhythm games, rhythm games... I have zero confidence!
違うか、ドンス...
Wait no, Don't St-
うわあああ！のじゃあ！
Waaaaah! Nojaa!
分かってたのに...
I knew it, though...
うぅ、分かってたのに...
Ugh, I knew it...
ひだ、左...
Lef-, left...
のじゃあ...
Nojaa...
の、の、のじゃあ...
No, no, nojaa...
え、もう怖くない。ね、もう怖くない
Eh, I'm not scared anymore. Look, I'm not scared anymore.
もう怖くない
I'm not scared anymore.
右上に目のゲージがある
There's an eye gauge in the top right.
ね、目のゲージはどういう仕組みなのじゃ？
Hey, how does that eye gauge work?
ね、目のゲージはどういう仕組みで溜まってくの？
What mechanism makes the eye gauge fill up?
右上のゲージ溜まると終わっちゃう？
If the top right gauge fills up, do you die?
ん？
Hm?
下がるとダメ？
Is it bad if it drops?
え、なんで？え、どうし...見られたら増える？
Wait, why? How does it... Does it increase if you're looked at?
え、じゃあ見られちゃダメ？
So you can't let them look at you?
え、じゃあずっと隠れてれば良くない？
Then wouldn't it be fine if I just stay hidden?
あ、そしたらパスタが温められない
Ah, but then I can't warm up the pasta.
むずい
That's tough.
むずいのじゃ
It's tough.
難しいのじゃ
It's hard.
ね、汗かいてきた
Hey, I've started sweating.
ね、パスタ温めしてたら汗かいてきたんじゃけど
Warming up pasta made me break into a sweat!
難しいのじゃ
It's so difficult.
え、でもゲーム分かってきた
Wait, but I'm starting to get the hang of this game.
ゲーム分かってきた
I'm getting the hang of it.
うん
Yeah.
ちょ、最後に1回やるのじゃ
Wait, I'll do one last run.
最後に1回やる、やらせていただきますのじゃ
One last time... I shall humbly take one more turn.
隠れてるやつで見られるとゲージが上がっちゃう？
Does the gauge go up when you're seen by the looking one?
ふーん、隠る場...隠れる場所も大事ってことか
Hmm, so the hid-... the hiding spot matters too, huh.
のじゃ
Indeed.
パスタじゃなくてわしが温まってきた
Instead of the pasta, I'm the one heating up.
わしが温まってきた
I'm all warmed up.
5分目指すのじゃ
Aiming for 5 minutes!
自分を越える
Surpassing myself.
5分を目指しますのじゃ
I shall aim for 5 minutes!
のじゃ
Yes.
いくのじゃー！
Here I go!
レフト、レフト、レフト、ライト、レフト、ライト...
Left, left, left, right, left, right...
急にドーンっていうのもね、怖いから嫌い
I hate sudden loud bangs because they're scary.
怖いからやめてほしい
They're scary, so I wish it would stop.
結構、あの...
Pretty much, um...
サラマンダーは音と光に弱くて
salamanders are sensitive to noise and light,
だからなんかその、あんまり音とか光で衝撃を与えないでほしくて
so I'd really rather not be shocked by sudden sounds and lights,
うーん、で、しかもさ、ホラゲって音もさ、光もさ、両方でさ
Yeah, and plus, horror games use both sound and light...
怖がらせてくるからさ
to scare the living daylights out of you,
怖い
so it's scary.
I see you
シーユー
"See you."
え、まだいる。まだいる、まだいる、まだいる...まだいる、まだいる、まだいる
Wait, it's still there. Still there, still there, still there... Still there, still there!
まだ居っておられた
It was still lingering there.
消える音わかんない、パパね
I can't tell the vanishing sound. That's papa, huh.
消える音わかんないのじゃ
I don't know the vanishing sound.
Don't look at me
ドントルックアットミー
Don't look at me.
アイ・ルック・ユー...ウォッチ...ウォッチ...
I look you... Watch... Watch...
なんか3回出てくると2、2回で終わる時がある
Sometimes it pops out 3 times, and sometimes it ends after 2.
あれ何なのじゃ？
What's that about?
Stay away.
のじゃ
Noja.
え、に...
Wait, t-
え、ちょっと！お前！何？何？お前何？お前何？お前！お前！お前！お前！
Wait, what?! You! What?! What are you?! What are you?! You! You! You! You!
ね、今のずる、今のずる！ね、今のわし分かった。今何が起きたか分かったわけ...あの、あの、あの...
Hey, that was cheap! That was unfair! Look, I get it now! I understand what happened... Um, um, um...
2、2連続で出た！2連で出た！2連で出た！2連で出たのじゃ！2連で出た！
Two- Two in a row! It came twice in a row! Twice in a row! It came two times in a row! Two in a row!
2連で出て...
It came twice in a row...
ってことは...
which means...
越えて越えてしなきゃいけなかったんだ！越えて越えてしなきゃいけなくて...
I had to jump across and across! I had to keep jumping across...
え、そ、そんなの知らないのじゃ...
Wait, I-I didn't know that...
そんなの知らないのじゃ...
I didn't know about that...
来たら越えなきゃいけないのか...
So if it comes, I have to jump across...?
ふぁあ...
Whew...
んー、それは知らなかったのじゃ...
Mmm, I had no idea about that...
ふー、難しかった。お、おしまい、おしまいのじゃ
Phew, that was tough. Th- That's all, it's over.
おしまいのじゃ
That's all.
怖かったのじゃ
It was so scary...
もう あの 息が浅くて浅くて仕方ないのじゃ
I mean, my breathing is just so shallow, I can't help it...
のじゃぁぁ...
Nojaaa...
お、おし、おしまいのじゃ
I-It's all over...
ちょ、ちょ、戻るのじゃ
W-Wait, let's go back.
雑談の...
To the chatting...
雑談のシーンに戻りましょのじゃ
Let's return to the chatting scene.
今日、今日わしかなり頑張ったんじゃない？
Didn't I do pretty well today?
今日わしかなり頑張ったんじゃないのじゃ？
Didn't I do pretty well today, noja?
結構...
Pretty...
結構、頑張ったんじゃない？
Didn't I do pretty well?
すごい... すごい怖かったよ、わし！
It was super... super scary for me!
ねえ？
Right?
わしすごい怖かったんだからね！
I was seriously terrified, you know!
ちなみに...
By the way...
ちな...
By...
なんか...
Like...
こ、怖かったんだからね！
I-It was scary, you know!
なんか...
Like...
しかもなんか、パスタ叩いてたし...
Plus, I was hitting pasta and stuff...
パスタ叩いてたし... あれ、な...
I was hitting pasta... What was...
な、何をやらされてたのじゃ、ガチ？
Seriously, what was I even being made to do?
何なのじゃ、このゲーム？
What is this game anyway?
このゲーム、な、何？
What... what is this game?
このゲーム、何？
What is this game?
このゲーム何、ガチ？
Seriously, what even is this game?
のじゃぁ...
Nojaaa...
え、フブキ先輩さあ...
Wait, Fubuki-senpai...
新人にゲームくれるなんて優しい先輩って思ったけど...
I thought she was a kind senpai for giving a newcomer a game, but...
なんか...
like...
狐に化かされたってこれのことなのじゃ？
Is this what they mean by "being tricked by a fox"?
化け狐ですのじゃ
She's a trickster fox.
あ、化け狐... 狐とか良くないか、先輩に向かって。失礼いたしましたのじゃ
Ah, calling a senpai a fox isn't good. My apologies!
今のなしでお願いいたしますのじゃ
Please pretend I didn't say that!
あの、言葉の、言葉の綾ですのじゃ
Um, it was just a figure of speech!
あの、いや、いい、いい先輩なのは分かっておりますのじゃ
I mean, I know she's a wonderful senpai!
あの、いや、優しい先輩なのはすごい分かっておりますのじゃ
I totally know she's a really kind senpai.
優しく、優しく声をあの、かけていただいてますのじゃ
She always reaches out to me so kindly.
のじゃ
Really.
あの、のじゃ、あの、フブキ先輩のファンの人、あの、違いますのじゃ
Um, Fubuki-senpai's fans, that's not what I meant!
すごい、い、良くて、優しくて、優しい先輩だと...
She's really great, kind, such a wonderful senpai...
どうだ？
How was that?
どうじゃ？
How's that?
いや...
No...
でもわし、わしホラゲ嫌いなの知ってる...
But she knows I hate horror games...
ねえ、わし、わしホラゲ、わしホラゲ怖がってるの知ってるのにさあ...
Hey, she knows I'm terrified of horror games, and yet...
なんか「ホラゲです」みたいの書かないでさあ...
without writing anything like "this is a horror game",...
「初心者でも安心アットホームなスパゲッティです」って書いてるの...
she wrote, "A cozy, beginner-friendly spaghetti"...
配信者的に？
From a streamer perspective?
のじゃぁ...
Nojaaa...
え、もしかしてさあ...
Wait, could it be...
え、おかゆ先輩にもゲームいただいたんじゃが...
Wait, I also received a game from Okayu-senpai...
え、なんかたんぽぽのゲームもそういう系？ 実はホラーみたいな？
Wait, is that dandelion game like that too? Like secretly a horror game?
ちょっと見、見てないんだっけ... どういうのか知らないんじゃけど...
I haven't really looked at it... I don't know what kind of game it is...
え、これからわし先輩から送られてくるゲーム全部...
Wait, from now on, all the games sent to me by senpais...
ホラーの可能性ありの心で...
with a mindset that there's a chance of horror...
ホラ、ホラーの可能性ありみたいな心で挑まなきゃいけないの？
do I have to take them on expecting they might be horror?
来週やろうと思ってたんじゃけど、たんぽぽ...
I was planning to play that dandelion game next week, though...
ちょ...
Wait...
い、一旦そのつもりで挑みますのじゃ
F-For now, I'll go into it expecting that.
そのつもりで挑みますのじゃ！
I'll take it on with that expectation!
のじゃぁ...
Nojaaa...
はぁ... 怖かったぁ...
Phew... That was scary...
恐ろしかったぁ...
It was terrifying...
しかもなんかパスタ叩いてる間さあ...
And besides, while I was hitting the pasta...
パスタ叩いてる間さあ...
while I was hitting the pasta...
あの正気を保つためにさあ、適当に喋ってたらなんか「ホラゲ毎週やる」みたいなこと言っちゃった...
to keep my sanity, I blabbed random stuff and ended up saying I'd play horror games every week...
なんか出来ないことは「やれる」「やる」って言っちゃダメ、みたいな...
Like, you shouldn't say you can or will do something you can't...
お、おおよそ、おおよそ毎週やるとかにするか...
M-Maybe I should make it "roughly every week"...
あ、なんか、なんじゃっけ...
Ah, like, what was it...
あの『8番出口』の続編みたいな...
Like that sequel to "Exit 8"...
あるじゃろ？ あれ、あれ気になってたから...
There's one, right? I was curious about that one...
やってみようかな、来週
maybe I'll try playing that next week.
ちょ、毎週かはあれだけど...
Well, "every week" might be a stretch, but...
ま、毎週かはあれだけど...
I-It might not be literally every week, but...
一旦来週もやってみようかな
maybe I'll give it a try next week too.
うん
Yeah.
一旦ね
Just for now.
ちょっとやってみようかな
Maybe I'll try it out.
うん、のじゃ
Yeah, noja.
のじゃぁ
Nojaaa.
ちょ、おおよそ、あの、あの、あの...
Wait, roughly, um, um, um...
こ、個人差あり！
I-Individual results may vary!
あの、あの週休2日と週休2日制的な感じで、あの...
Like the difference between "two days off a week" and "two-day weekend system", um...
あの、1日しか休めないみたいな、そう、跨がってる可能性あり
like you might only get one day off, yeah, it might straddle across weeks.
そう、みたいな感じにしよう
Yeah, let's go with something like that.
そう、そういう感じにするのじゃ
Right, that's how we'll treat it.
うん、うん、のじゃ
Yeah, yeah, noja.
完全週休2日じゃないやつ。そう
The one that isn't a strict two-day weekend. Yeah.
そうそうそうそう、完全じゃない系の...
Right right right, the non-strict type...
それぐらいの認識でやるのじゃ。うん
I'll do it with that kind of understanding. Yeah.
うん、うん、うん、のじゃ
Yeah, yeah, yeah, noja.
え、これ、チェーンメールってそういうこと？ 送っていいの？
Wait, is this what chain mail is about? Can I send it?
え、送るなら絶対つづりだけど... つづりもらってるって聞いたのじゃ
Wait, if I send it, definitely to Tsuzuri, but... I heard Tsuzuri already got it.
つづりもらってるって聞いたから...
Since I heard Tsuzuri already got it...
すずにもらってるって聞いたから...
Since I heard she got it from Suzu...
ソフィアか...
Sophia, or...
きょーこなのじゃが...
...Kyouko, though...
あ、でもね
Ah, but you know...
え、なんかSteamのアカウント作りたてで
Well, I think if your Steam account is brand new...
ギフト送れなかったんだよな、確か。
...you can't send gifts, if I remember correctly.
どうだったっけか？
How did that work again?
ちょ、それも確認してみるのじゃ。
Let me check on that as well.
ちょっとあのギフト機能が解放されてない可能性があり、
There's a chance the gifting feature hasn't been unlocked yet,
我、我が新人に付き...
and seeing as I'm a newcomer...
うん
Yeah.
から、ちょっとその機能とかを確認しつつ、検討させていただきますのじゃ。
So while checking those features, I'll take it into consideration.
うん
Yeah.
のじゃ
Indeed.
感謝の気持ちを込めてきょーこに。
Giving it to Kyouko to show my gratitude...
まあ確かにきょーこに送っても、きょーこはなんか...
Well, true, even if I send it to Kyouko, she could...
1時間とかやりできそうだしな。
...probably play it for an hour or so.
ありなのじゃ。
That could work.
うん
Yeah.
のじゃ
Yep.
はあー、びっくりしたー。
Phew, that scared me.
分かったー
Alright.
ちょ、なんかあのミスってなんか画面映しちゃったとこ、まりちゃんに聞いてみるのじゃ。
I'll ask Mari-chan about the part where I accidentally showed my screen.
これあのアーカイブ残していい？って聞いてみる。
I'll ask her, "Is it okay to keep the archive up?"
うん
Yeah.
多分、多分そんなや、やばいものは映ってないと思うけど、
I don't think anything crazy was shown, probably,
念のため確認してみるのじゃ。
but I'll check with her just to be safe.
のじゃー
Yep.
明日はリズム天国で遊びますのじゃ！
Tomorrow, we'll be playing Rhythm Heaven!
うん
Yeah.
であの、明後日はマシュマロ雑談をしようと思ってて...
And, the day after tomorrow, I'm thinking of doing a Marshmallow chat stream...
マシュマロ雑談をしようと思ってるから...
Since I'm planning to do a Marshmallow chat stream...
えっと...
Umm...
TwitterにマシュマロのURLを貼ってるから、
I posted the Marshmallow URL on Twitter,
質問を募集しておりますのじゃ！
so I'm collecting questions!
お願いしますのじゃ！
Please send them in!
えっ、もしかして明日のリズム天国に備えて今日音ゲーの練習していた？
Wait, was I practicing rhythm games today in preparation for Rhythm Heaven tomorrow?
そういうこと？
Is that what that was?
そういうことのじゃ。
That's exactly it.
まだ受け付けておりますのじゃ！
Submissions are still open!
エゴサよりいっぱい集まるから、
Since I get way more than from vanity searches,
見るの楽しいのじゃ。
it's really fun to look through them.
あの、全部は配信で読めないんだけど、
Umm, though I can't read all of them on stream,
ちゃんと見させていただいておりますのじゃ。
I make sure to read every one of them.
ありがとのじゃ！
Thank you!
じゃあ...
Well then...
明日は、えー、19時から
Tomorrow, um, from 19:00...
リズム天国配信でお会いしましょうのじゃ。
...let's meet up for the Rhythm Heaven stream!
スケジュールも明日のうちに出したいなって思ってるので、
I want to put out the schedule sometime tomorrow too,
お待ちくださいのじゃー！
so please stay tuned!
よいしょ。
Alright.
今日の配信はおしまいですのじゃ。
That wraps up today's stream.
また、明日の配信でお会いしましょう！
Let's meet again in tomorrow's stream!
さらばじゃーーー！
Farewell~~~!
ご視聴感謝なのじゃ！
[Thanks for watching!]